Nik Rykov

Software Developer | Protocol Engineer UI/UX Designer | Team Manager

About Me

Experienced software developer, product/protocol engineer, designer, founder and an individual with the skills necessary to push projects to the production stage and ensure smooth growth afterwards.

Skills

Protocol Design & Research, JavaScript, C++, Vue.js/Nuxt, Node.js N-API Addons, UI/UX Design, Diagramming, Startup Leadership, Project Management, Public Speaking, Blockchain, Philosophy.

Experience

Highlayer

Role: Founder/CTO Time: 2023-2024

At Highlayer, I led a team developing a state-of-the-art architecture for a high-throughput bitcoin rollup, implementing the essential network components and successfully launching testnet of the product.

WeaveVM

Role: Technical Advisor

Time: 2024-Present

I advise WeaveVM on technical details of its product, ensuring the architecture of the product is sustainable and reliable while remaining decentralized and trustless.

Stargaze.zone

Role: Software Developer (Part-time)

Time: 2022-2023

At Stargaze, I worked on developing Stargaze Names and the toolset around it. The toolset included Stargaze Pages, DNS server, DNS registry backend/UI, Handshake integration, etc.

Arweave

Role: Software Developer

Time: 2021-2023

At Arweave, I designed ecosystem tooling, architected systems and innovative applications/protocols that push forward the ecosystem and state of the cryptocurrency space as a whole. My research and development helped kickstart the AO project - hyperparallel smart contract platform. I also prototyped first data access network during that time.

Handshake

Role: Ecosystem Contributor

Time: 2021-Present

The idea of decentralized, trustless domains/websites appealed to me, thus I joined the development of the Handshake ecosystem by contributing to the project and various ecosystem tools, including bridge to traditional web, second-level (SLD) domain tooling, coin bridges, resolvers and more.

FindADiscord.com

Role: Sole Developer Time: 2019-Present

After developing a bot catalog, I joined forces with creators of /r/discordservers (largest community for discovery of the discord servers) to make an application that to this day helps people in connecting with communities they might be interested in.

Top Bots Catalog (shut down)

Role: Founder Time: 2017-2019

My first major venture as a developer and founder (after developing Discord bots).

I developed majority of the codebase and managed to get service to 120,000 monthly-active users.

Research

Cryptographic Subkeys in Decentralized Applications

Year: 2023

Link: https://github.com/angrymouse/papers/blob/main/subaccounts.md

Data Access Networks

Year: 2022

Link: https://github.com/angrymouse/papers/blob/main/data-access-networks.md

Relay-ring signature-based automated wallet system

Year: 2022

Link: https://github.com/angrymouse/papers/blob/main/relay-ring-protocol.md

Tradable NFTs in absence of smart contracts

Year: 2023

Link: https://arweave.net/oIrgzZt3UBW9ct_WzIVTx06X01w1AJKJEsrncJJ2IAI

Highlayer: A New Architecture for Effective Rollups

Year: 2024

Link: https://highlayer.io/litepaper.pdf

EIP-7689: Smart Blobs

Year: 2024

Link: https://ethereum-magicians.org/t/erc-7689-smart-blobs/19672

Education

Kharkiv Lyceum №119

Contact

Email: rykov.nikas@gmail.com

Website: nik.technology

Telegram: Qangermouse